<eml:eml xmlns:eml="https://eml.ecoinformatics.org/eml-2.2.0"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xmlns:stmml="http://www.xml-cml.org/schema/stmml-1.2"
         packageId="doi:10.18739/A2X921J1G"
         system="https://arcticdata.io"
         scope="system">
  <dataset>
    <alternateIdentifier>b4bef56c-143f-4152-879b-ec66509a8bd1</alternateIdentifier>
    <title>EML-GBIF 2.2.0 template</title>
    <creator>
      <organizationName/>
      <individualName>
        <givenName/>
        <surName/>
      </individualName>
      <positionName/>
      <address>
        <city/>
        <administrativeArea/>
        <postalCode/>
        <country/>
      </address>
      <phone phonetype="voice"/>
      <electronicMailAddress/>
      <onlineUrl/>
    </creator>
    <pubDate/>
    <abstract>
      <para/>
    </abstract>
    <keywordSet>
      <keyword/>
      <keywordThesaurus>None</keywordThesaurus>
    </keywordSet>
    <intellectualRights>
      <para/>
    </intellectualRights>
    <distribution>
      <online>
        <url/>
      </online>
    </distribution>
    <coverage>
      <geographicCoverage>
        <geographicDescription/>
        <boundingCoordinates>
          <westBoundingCoordinate>-43.5025</westBoundingCoordinate>
          <eastBoundingCoordinate>-43.5025</eastBoundingCoordinate>
          <northBoundingCoordinate>68.892</northBoundingCoordinate>
          <southBoundingCoordinate>68.892</southBoundingCoordinate>
        </boundingCoordinates>
      </geographicCoverage>
      <temporalCoverage>
        <rangeOfDates>
          <beginDate>
            <calendarDate/>
          </beginDate>
          <endDate>
            <calendarDate/>
          </endDate>
        </rangeOfDates>
      </temporalCoverage>
    </coverage>
    <contact id="ref_contact_3">
      <organizationName/>
      <individualName>
        <givenName/>
        <surName/>
      </individualName>
      <positionName/>
    </contact>
    <project>
      <title/>
      <personnel>
        <organizationName/>
        <individualName>
          <givenName/>
          <surName/>
        </individualName>
        <electronicMailAddress/>
        <role/>
      </personnel>
      <abstract>
        <para>This project will further understanding of ocean-ice-atmosphere interaction around the Jakobshavn Isbrae and Disko Bay region of west Greenland, with a particular focus on the role of sea surface temperature and sea ice variability in modulating past outlet glacier behavior and ice sheet/cap mass balance (snowfall and melt) over the past two centuries. The PIs will reconstruct past environmental conditions in the Disko and Baffin Bay region based on new glaciochemical and stratigraphic records from three 100-m deep ice cores, several firn cores, and geophysical studies from three sites surrounding Disko Bay. Their field activities will commence in 2013 with the primary ice coring activity in 2014 and lab and computation work following to derive climate reconstructions from the cores. The results will complement recent glaciological studies of regional ice dynamic behavior, as well as recent paleoceanographic and glacial geologic reconstructions of conditions from this area and era. Das and Frey will each supervise a full-time PhD student, and Evans will supervise undergraduate research assistants and senior theses. A high school science teacher will also participate in the field work and interact with students at his school in Massachusetts as well as from the ice.</para>
      </abstract>
      <funding/>
    </project>
  </dataset>
</eml:eml>
